Phan Hoang Vy Thao

UX/UI Designer

66 I have worked as a Front-end Developer for two years before realizing my interest in designing technological products.

Now I am a UX/UI Designer and I really enjoy my work. In the future, I plan to pursue a career as a Product Design Specialist.

Day of birth

September 1995



phvythao@gmail.com



Phone

(+84) 96 995 2523

District 12, Ho Chi Minh City

Portfolio



Personal website vythaor.design



Behance @vythaor





@vythaor

Languages



English Intermediate

Education



Industrial University of Ho Chi Minh City

Bachelor of Computer Science GPA: 2.8/4

Sep 2013 - May 2017



KEYFRAME Training

Product design course Dec 2019 - June 2020

Experience

Feb 2023 - now UX/UI Designer

FPT Software

Oct 2022 - Jan 2023 Product designer

Inspire Lab Technology

Jan 2021 - July 2022 UX/UI designer **Amaris Consulting**

UX/UI designer consultant

Prudential Vietnam Assurance Private Itd

Oct 2020 - now UX/UI designer Freelancer

Dec 2019 - Sep 2020 UX/UI designer Spring Knowledge Global

Sep 2017 - Dec 2019 Front end developer Spring Knowledge Global Creates fantastic UI designs and fully interactive prototypes. Building and using design systems, style guides and pattern libraries.

Applies User Centered Design principles in UX process.

Conduct user research to gain insights and optimize designs.

Working closely with product owners, developers and customer stakeholders.

Research, analysis and design an internal project.

Build design systems.

Join product development team work in Scrum process as a product designer.

Meeting weekly to improve UI/UX issues.

Work with Product Owner team and Front-end Developer team to ensure products match requirements, user experiences rules and design systems.

UX/UI design consultant at Prudential

Design UX/UI in web, tablet and mobile for internal products.

Work closely with the Business Analytist team to propose mockup and final design solutions.

Support the Development team in transferring design and asset files into apps.

Identify and improve user experience issues. Find UI problems in UAT applications.

Manage large design files and ensuring that all screens match design system of Prudential.

Bring creative design ideas to products.

Join an e-commerce startup as a designer.

Create graphics, apps, and websites design for products.

Work as a designer in a freelancer team.

Make sketches from business requirements.

Use Figma to create web and mobile projects.

Review visual design and following Design System such as Material Design, Ant Design to create design versions.

Discuss with the Development team and receiving feedbacks to improve the designs.

Participate in Ideathon events to generate idea for new internal products.

Implement websites using Javascript framework such as ReactJs and VueJs.

Guarantee, maintain and fix product bugs.

Using Express, Loopback NodeJs to maintain and expand server source code

Phan Hoang Vy Thao

UX/UI Designer

I have worked as a Front-end Developer for two years before realizing my interest in designing technological products.

Now I am a UX/UI Designer and I really enjoy my work. In the future, I plan to pursue a career as a Product Design Specialist.



phvythao@gmail.com



Address
District 12, Ho Chi Minh City

Portfolio



Behance

@vythaor



Languages



Education



Industrial University of Ho Chi Minh City

Bachelor of Computer Science GPA: 2.8/4

Sep 2013 - May 2017

KEYFRAME® Keyframe Training

Product design course
Dec 2019 - June 2020

Highlight projects



Skills

